inspire2rise.com 2019-04-06

# Privacy Policy - Inspire2Rise L.L.P - All you need to know!

If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

At www.inspire2rise.com, the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information is received and collected by www.inspire2rise.com and how it is used.

## Who we are

We are Inspire2Rise L.L.P based out of New Delhi, India. Our website address is: https://www.inspire2rise.com. It was founded by [Aditya Nath Jha](https://www.inspire2rise.com/aditya-nath-jha "Aditya Nath Jha") in 2011 and Inspire2Rise is a registered trademark of Inspire2Rise L.L.P. So any usage online without explicity permission or consent is prohibited.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

[](https://www.inspire2rise.com/privacy-policy/privacy-policy-inspire2rise-llp)The data that we collect is only required to better serve advertisements and/or enhance the experience of a user that is logged in to the site or wishes to comment upon an article.

Personal data is not just created by your interactions with our site. Personal data is also generated from technical processes such as contact forms, comments, cookies, analytics, and third-party embeds. And we will discuss each in detail.

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to our website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Contact forms

We keep contact form submissions for a certain period for ease of contact but we do not use the information submitted through them for marketing purposes.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to save your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

We use Google Analytics tracking which is non intrusive and does not impact or hinder the privacy of our users in any way. We have disabled location based analytics for our visitors from EU for better compliance with GDPR laws. Our web hosting might collect some anonymous analytics data.

## Who we share your data with

We don’t share your data with anyone. Be default the plugins we use might collect some user data about you and you can read most of the plugins’ privacy policy below.

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

### How we protect your data

We use SSL on our site which ensure that your experience is secure and encrypted at all points of time. We also don’t share your data with any unauthorized third parties apart from our Ad providers or spam protection services.

### What data breach procedures we have in place

In the event of a data breach no personally identifiable user data can be leaked from our site. This is because the only data we need to collect is used for advertising purposes and it’s not pin point data which can compromise any user’s sensitive information.

### What third parties we receive data from

We receive data like IP-Address location etc. from our traffic analysis services, and use services like CloudFlare, Google Analytics and Google Adsense.

### What personal data we collect and why we collect it?

We collect information about visitors who comment on Sites that use our Akismet anti-spam service. The information we collect depends on how the User sets up Akismet for the Site, but typically includes the commenter’s IP address, user agent, referrer, and Site URL (along with other information directly provided by the commenter such as their name, username, email address, and the comment itself).

### Security Logs

The IP address of visitors, user ID of logged in users, and username of login attempts are conditionally logged to check for malicious activity and to protect the site from specific kinds of attacks. Examples of conditions when logging occurs include login attempts, log out requests, requests for suspicious URLs, changes to site content, and password updates. This information is retained for 14 days.

## Who we share your data with

This site is scanned for potential malware and vulnerabilities by Sucuri’s SiteCheck. We do not send personal information to Sucuri; however, Sucuri could find personal information posted publicly (such as in comments) during their scan. For more details, please see [Sucuri’s privacy policy](https://sucuri.net/privacy).

## How long we retain your data

Security logs are retained for 14 days.

## Where we send your data

This site is part of a network of sites that protect against distributed brute force attacks. To enable this protection, the IP address of visitors attempting to log into the site is shared with a service provided by ithemes.com. For privacy policy details, please see the [iThemes Privacy Policy](https://ithemes.com/privacy-policy).

**Log Files :**  
Like many other Web sites, www.inspire2rise.com makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider ( ISP ), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and the number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable as is mentioned in our privacy policy further.

**Double Click** **  DART Cookie :**  
.:: Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on www.inspire2rise.com.  
.:: Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to www.inspire2rise.com and other sites on the Internet.  
.:: Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL – http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html

### **Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site**.

Our advertising partners include ….  
Google Ad-sense.

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on www.inspire2rise.com send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

www.inspire2rise.com has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers. Our privacy policy is strictly limited to things within our control domain.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. www.inspire2rise.com’s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of (or privacy policy of), such other advertisers or websites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.
